gugutz Tweaks Collection v0.4

About this edition
About the importing methods
cmdlines usage sample
RunOnceEx usage sample
Services tweaks
History of Changes

Created using as base the Registry Tweaks PT 4 February 3rd, from the MSFN Forums, created by John Cronk aka "Johnny Do" and modified by Glent.

The difference between this and the original collection is that in this the tweaks are organized in separate files for better organization, and i mantain it now, correting errors and eventually adding more tweaks.

If you have any sugestions or things to add to the files, please feel free to contact me at gugutz@gmail.com or send a Private Message at the MSFN Forums.

Also visit My Site for future releases and other stuff.

Thank you for using my collection, and see you around. :)

About this edition

In this edition i았e added some new files inside a new folder called "essentials". The purpose of this is to make a folder in witch you can have only essential tweaks that are in no way harmfull to the system and are ready to be used in a Unattended Windows Setup, instead of opening file by file and removing tweaks you don앖 like.

Inside the "essentials" folder, you will find 4 files:

tweaks_en.reg - This is the file that contains the main tweaks.
services.reg - This is the file to tweak the System Services.
other-software.reg - In this one there are a lot of tweaks for various Non-MS Software. The intention of this file is to get the registry ready to whenever you install a application, you won앖 have to configured it to get it installed the way you want (like not installing Google Toolbar when installing Skype, set NOD32 to full protection withou asking when you first install it, etc...)
registry_bookmarks.reg - This one adds some bookmarks to the registry, like My Computer and My Network Places, so if you plan to make modifications after applying the tweaks, you can easily acess the main keys in the registry without having to look for them.

Then first you should decide witch package you want to use: The essentials or the one that contains all the tweaks.

If you choose to use the folder with all the tweaks, please be aware that this one is inside the package only for informational purposes. You MUST NOT go over applying the tweaks before revising them. Then if you choose the package with all the tweaks, here is what you should do:

Open each .reg file, read them completely, and coment (with a semi-colon -> " ; ", without the quotes). Leave "as is" only the tweaks that you want.

By doing that, when the time to import the tweaks comes, the registry editor will jump the commented entries. This way, you would have made your very own personal collection, that suits better to you machine specifications and to your taste.

Top

About the Importing Methods

I앐 not sure exactly why, but some tweaks do not "fix" using only cmdlines.txt. Maybe it is because Windows makes some final adjustments at first login, maybe not. That is why it is better also use RunOnceEx.cmd to make sure everything get imported right.

Bellow you can read usage samples for cmdlines.txt and RunOnceEx. Just keep reading...

Top

cmdlines.txt usage sample

To make things easier, create a batch file called anything you like. In this exemple i앏l be using "tweaks.cmd". Create it inside the $OEM$ folder, open it with your favorite text editor and paste this:

cmdow @ /HID
@echo off

FOR %%D IN (d: e: f: g: h: i: j: k: l: m: n: o: p: q: r: s: t: u: v: w: x:) DO IF EXIST %%D\WIN51IP SET CDROM=%%D
SET TWEAKS=%CDROM%\Setup\Tweaks

regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\tweaks_en.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\services.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\other-software.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\favoritos-registro.reg

Change the line "SET TWEAKS=%CDROM%\Setup\Tweaks" to whatever is the path to the tweaks in your XP CD.

After that open your cmdlines.txt and add this line in any place available there:

"tweaks.cmd"

This will make "tweaks.cmd" to be called at T-12 of setup. Then the batch file will detect your CD (with the FOR statement) and import the tweaks to the registry.

(IF you앇 like to make your own personal package of tweaks using the folder with all the tweaks rathen than the "essentials", the code to be put in the "tweaks.cmd" file would be this:)

regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\context_menus.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\folder_view_and_taskbar.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\general_customation.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\general_settings.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\internet_explorer.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\logon.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\media_player-windows_media_player.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\multimedia.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\other_software.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\visual_effects.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\outlook_express.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\security.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\SP2_only.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\start_menu_and_taskbar.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\startup-shutdown.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\system_performance.reg
regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\unsorted_and_untested.reg

Top

RunOnceEx.cmd usage sample

After performing the procedures above with cmdlines.txt, open your RunOnceEx.cmd and add these lines:

REG ADD %KEY%\001 /VE /D "Applying Registry Tweaks" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 1 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\tweaks_en.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 2 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\services.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 3 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\other_software.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 4 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\registry_bookmarks.reg" /f

beeing %tweaks% a variable that indicates the path to the folder in witch the tweaks are.
If needed, create one, using the same line at the cmdlines.txt example above.

Just don앖 forget to change the numbers after the %KEY% variable to the corresponding number in you ROE sequence.

(IF you앇 like to make your own personal package of tweaks using the folder with all the tweaks rathen than the "essentials", the code to be put in the "RunOndeEx.cmd" file would be this:)

REG ADD %KEY%\001 /VE /D "Applying Registry Tweaks" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 1 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\context_menus.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 2 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\folder_view_and_taskbar.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 3 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\general_customation.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 4 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\general_settings.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 5 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\internet_explorer.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 6 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\logon.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 7 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\media_player-windows_media_player.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 8 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\multimedia.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 9 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\other_software.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 10 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\visual_effects.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 11 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\outlook_express.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 12 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\security.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 13 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\SP2_only.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 14 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\start_menu_and_taskbar.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 15 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\startup-shutdown.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 16 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\system_performance.reg" /f
REG ADD %KEY%\001 /V 17 /D "regedit.exe /s %tweaks%\unsorted_and_untested.reg" /f

Top

System Services

These Services Tweaks were obtained based on the Black Viper압 Article about "Removing Uneeded Services", at Majors Geeks site.

Inside the files there is only the names of the services. For a brief info about what each services does, visit my site

If youre going to make your own personal services tweak file, YOU REALLY SHOULD VISIT The Article from witch these tweaks were obtained to read more information about these tweaks and choose the ones that suits best to your machine.

I앐 releasing a personal tweak file, Services.gugutz.reg in "all" folder, witch should contain the Services Tweaking according to my machine and proper adjustments for most machine around there.

You may notice in Black Viper압 Article that there are 27 Services that are setled "Disabled" for all Configurations (except Default Pro, but since you are tweaking your services, i presume the reason for this is that you don앖 like MS deciding witch Service should be running on your machine...).

So those are disabled in the "services.reg" file within the "essentials" folder.

These services are:

Alerter
Background Intelligent Transfer Service
ClipBook
Error Reporting Service
Help and Support
Indexing Service
IPSEC Services
Messenger
Net Login
Network DDE
Network DDE DSDM
Performance Logs and Alerts
QoS RSVP
Remote Desktop Help Session Manager
Remote Registry Service
Routing and Remote Access
Secondary Logon
Security Accounts Manager
Smart Card
Smart Card Helper
System Restore Service
TCP/IP NetBIOS Helper Service
Telnet
Uninterruptible Power Supply
Upload Manager
WebClient
Windows Time

You may also notice that there are 10 Services that have the relevancy "Vital" or "Yes, you need it". These services should be setled AT LEAST to Manual, and, in most cases, to Automatic. You can disable these Services, but do it only if you really know what youre doing. Even so, DO NOT disable Remote Procedure Call (RPC) and Workstation, since most services depends on them, and you stop them, all the others will also stop , and then your system will probably (almost for certain) die.

These Services are:

Application Management
Event Log
Network Connections
Plug and Play
Remote Procedure Call (RPC)
Windows Audio
Windows Installer
Windows Management Instrumentation
Windows Management Instrumentation Driver Extension
Workstation

Thats it. Any bugs will hopefully be corrected on the next version.

Top

History of Changes

January 09, 2007. v0.4

Added - Tweaks to change other visual stuff rathen than windows defaults (like use Royale Noir, use Segoe UI as system font, etc...)
Added - Some new tweaks inside "other_software.reg" file
Added - The package now has a new folder with only essential tweaks to a unattended installation.
Removed - "Change Transition Effect to Menus and Tips using Fade", 앆ause it was restarting my PC and the ones i installed (and took me about 4 days to find out this ******).
Removed - The batch files inside the package. There are instrucions inside the readme file instead.

November 02, 2006. v0.3

Added - Folders to separate the tweaks according the it압 category (general, internet-networking, services)
Added - New tweaks to 56k dial-up connections in the "internet-network" folder, based on the TweakXP Article for Dial-Up Tweaks. Read the info inside the REG file..
Changed - "HungAppTimeout" and "WaitToKillAppTimeout" changed to 1500 = 1,5 seconds to increase stability while closing apps (thanks DL.)
Changed - A new and colorfull "readme" file using XHTML.
Removed - Duplicate entries "MaxConnectionsPerServer" and "NoDriveTypeAutoRun" (thanks DL again :P)

October 30, 2006. v0.2

Added - Tweaks for TuneUp Utilities 2006 in "Other_software.reg"
Added - 2 Tweaks for Macromedia Shockwave 10 in "Other_software.reg" (to not update and collect statistics)
Fixed - Some idention and ortographical misleads that were left in the previous version.
Removed - Duplicate entrie "Internet Connection - Firewall (ICF) / Sharing (ICS)" in all the Services tweaks files, since it is the same as "Windows Firewall/Internet Connection Sharing (ICS)". I added some comments to explain it better to ppl who don앖 use SP2.
Important Change - Removed the Services.reg file and created a new folder, "Services", in witch there are 6 reg files for tweaking the XP Services, based on the Black Viper압 article on "Removing Uneeded Services" at Major Geeks site. PLEASE RED THE README FILE BEFORE APPLYING THESE TWEAKS. I made a section on the readme file with important info about these new tweaks.

October 27, 2006. v0.1

Added - tweaks for Adobe Reader 7 series
Fixed - Idented the original files to the get more space and be better organized.
Fixed - Some ortographical errors, wrong entries and coments from the original file
Changed - Splitted the Single Tweaks File into 17 independant .reg files.
Changed - Removed the coment tags of each reg file on the first line, witch identify the file as being a registry file to be used with "Windows Registry Editor Version 5.00". Be carefull before double clicking in any file.

Top